All
right. Are we ready to go here? Jay,
it's great seeing you, man. It's great
having you back with us. Why don't you
get us started?
>> Well, how would you convert?
>> All right, let's have somebody else get
us started. [laughter]
>> Hopson, you got something?
Um, you know, I don't throw anything off
on or off the table with with Trey in in
ter we're excited about attacking this
off seasonason. We have resources to
attack the offseason in a big way and we
want to do that. Uh, in terms of how
we're going to do that, how we're going
to uh allocate our resources. Um, you
know, who is it going to be on our own
free agents? What's our intentions
there? I'm not going to get into that
right here. It's just not the time to uh
announce that to the rest of the league.
So, um that's the best way I can answer
that.
>> In your evaluation of running backs,
what's the priority for you for carrying
versus pass protection? For example,
there's a running back out of your
backyard in Cincinnati. Great production
in Oklahoma, Wisconsin, and he's also a
great pass protector. Is a guy like Ty
Walker on your roster?
>> Yeah, we try to keep a lot of people on
our radars for sure. And um you know,
for us individually, the way that we
operate, you know, pass protection is a
big thing. You know, you obviously got
to have skill to carry the ball and
you've got to have skill to be a pass
game threat to some degree and you've
got to be able to protect. And uh and
the position with the Cincinnati Bengals
is is is pretty demanding. It really is.
And uh uh that that's what Chase came in
and really embraced is is how do I
become a complete back and stay on the
field and he became a pass protector. He
became a threat in the pass game. And uh
he's obviously a very talented ball
carrier. So we look at all three and uh
we don't really rank them one, two, or
three. They they kind of got to have it
all for for us to feel like they can be
an every down contributor for us.
>> How do you balance desire to upgrade the
roster this season with potential
extensions turn.
>> Yeah, in terms of uh extensions and how
that affects the rest of it. Sometimes
you can do extensions within their the
cap count that you currently have and
sometimes you can't. Um we we juggle all
those things that we have a number of
resources and and we're going to use
them the best way that we can to improve
as many areas of our roster as we can.
We have things that we uh definitely
want to get done and we've put a lot of
time into it. We've had a lot of people
involved in trying to sketch out the
best plan. Now, the best plan never goes
as orchestrated, but we have a good plan
in place and and we're looking to
improve our team in every way we can.
And if that's with extensions, so be it.
two linebackers later. Did that process
that approach to rebuilding the defense
teach?
>> Yeah, you know, we're always trying to
fit, you know, where we're picking to
the talent level and and we don't want
to just reach for a need. And so we're
picking 10th this year. We're not going
to rank 10 of the same position in order
and take the 10th best guy at his
position. So, you always have to be
flexible in terms of the positions. Um,
but yeah, there are definite areas of
our football team that we're looking to
uh to enhance and uh and and it can come
from within, but it it has to some of it
has to come from external sources and
and the draft is is a big chance for us
to to really hit on guys that can be
long-term contributors for us. And then
we'll look to free agency and maybe with
some extensions and uh you know we'll
try to fill it in the best we can.
>> Yeah. A AI. Yeah. I you know we we
dabble in AI. Yeah. We we try to use as
many resources as we can. Um you know
it's it's still new to us. Uh analytics
is not new to us. Analytics has been
around for a long time just in different
forms. Uh it it's become more prevalent
and it's become more robust over time,
but it's been around ever since somebody
uh timed to 40, that's an analytic. And
so as long as that's been around or how
tall are you or uh you know how much do
you weigh, those are all analytics as
well. So, it's grown in importance uh
and AI continues to develop over time
and uh and we're trying to stay up to
speed on it for sure.
you know, we're getting a lot of
variation there because a lot of guys
are staying in longer. Um, I don't
believe a 25year-old is old. I think a
25year-old is young. Uh, still has a lot
of football left in his body. So, it
it's it's it's a data point. It's
something we're aware of. It might
affect the longevity down the road, but
sometimes it can also be be a benefit.
uh the guy's a little more mature in his
body, a little more uh stable maybe in
how he conducts himself uh in his
personal life or whatever it is. But,
you know, age is is a number. Guys are
playing longer the these years. Uh and
and so it's a factor, but it's not a big
factor for us. While he might spend
while he might2
>> in 2021 and 2022
I'm kind of forward looking so I'm
trying to think of exactly what all
happened in those years but yeah we're
going to attack it you know and and try
to build our roster from all sources and
the draft is one of those sources free
agency is another perhaps resigning some
of our impending free agents is another
extension so they don't get to free
agency is another way to do it but we're
going to look at all areas and we're
going to try to attack this off season
and fit our needs with the right people
and that's that's what our focus is and
we're excited about it because we have
resources to go out and and do some
things you guys
kind of
from teammates. How much does that
impact
>> with Dalton Risyner? You know, he um
came in late to the process, really fit
in. You know, I thought we were ended up
being a great fit for him in how we play
and he became a great fit for us and and
came in and filled the need for us. Uh
did a nice job, fit in well. I've got a
ton of respect for him, really enjoyed
getting to know him. He's really uh you
know a fantastic person just to be
around in the locker room on a
day-to-day basis and uh he's a guy that
we've talked to and we'll see if we can
get something done. He's got decisions
to make and we've got decisions to make
and and he's a guy that we like a lot
>> during this time of year
but the concept of
How would you guys
know
your championship window?
[snorts]
>> So, the questions on whether we're all
in or not. I I've been doing this a long
time. I've never not been all in. We are
all in. We are trying to get the best
team possible with the resources we
have. Um, you know, last year we went
all in. We signed over $400 million
worth of contracts going all in. That's
what we do. We want to be all in. We're
trying to put the best roster together
every year. And this year is no
different.
you have
already
factor into how you guys now
>> um you know I've always been very
impressed with Al and and the thing Al
Al is very flexible you know he can take
what he has and make a good defense out
of it he can and I believe that and I
think he will do that. Uh he has a
vision for what he wants to be and it's
my job to go out and fill the needs that
will fulfill that vision that he has.
And uh so yeah, do I do I have 100%
confidence that uh we'll get that done
together? I do. I believe in Al. I
believe in Zach. I think their vision is
the right vision and it's on the guys in
the personnel department with their help
to go out and identify guys and then see
if we can get them signed. You know,
it's a two-part thing. You can uh you
can want somebody and maybe they don't
want you or they uh go somewhere else
and and they're not available to you.
But but we want to identify the right
ones. Then we want to go out and attack
and see if we can get them to
Cincinnati.
>> We're back to Trey. Yeah. I you know I'm
not going to I'm not going to talk about
how we're going to deploy our resources
and and what our intention is with the
the track the tag or you know I'm not
going to close any doors on any player
that we've had or any of our free agents
up here today. I'm just not going to do
that. Trey's been a great player for us.
He didn't have the year he wanted this
year. We didn't have the year we wanted
this year. Those are factors and we'll
see where we go from there. But in terms
of how we're going to deploy the tag, if
we are going to, that's not something
I'm going to talk about here.
How important was this specifically?
>> Yeah, it's a data point. You know, I
think AI would have told us that it was
pretty good and uh it was fast. You
know, that's a position depending on how
you want to play them and we want guys
that can run and cover and play in man
uh cover deep balls. Um and and he
showed that he had those traits. He
showed it on tape. So the 40 time was
more of a a confirmation of what we
believed he was, what we saw on tape. If
the 40 time doesn't confirm that one way
or the other, we go back to the tape and
we determine whether his playing speed
is good enough or not. But it's always
comforting to know that a player you
feel is fast comes out and runs fast.
Then you're pretty confident in your
assessment.
the conversation with which which one
was that?
>> Yeah, I haven't had a real good time to
sit down and and have a debrief with
Joe. Uh if that's what you're asking. Um
I' I've had a few conversations with him
and I always enjoy our interactions. I
really do. Um I can tell you he doesn't
feel the season went well and neither do
I. So, I I think we're aligned on that.
Um,
>> yeah.
>> Yeah, Seattle did a nice job and they
had a very good front and they had a
physical front and they had a wave of
guys that kept coming through and that's
something every team want. You know, you
you ask anybody in my position with any
of the other teams, they want that
defensive line. They want the wave and
and we would like to get to the point
where we have a couple different groups
we can deploy in there and keep them
fresh and uh and really get after the
passer. And you got to stop the run in
order to get after the passer. And it
was impressive to see, you know,
Seattle's Dline play and and they had a
great scheme and uh congrats to them.
John's a good friend of mine.
with Stewart. How did you feel like he
played and what his role maybe looks
like going forward and how much do you
have to have a good feel for that to
understand how you're gonna try to
attack free agency in a position like
>> you know I'm excited about Shamar. All
of us are excited about Shamar. The
first year didn't go the way he wanted.
You know, he didn't have a ton of
practice. He played healthy in the first
game and then he wasn't healthy the rest
of the year. And uh that's tough on a
young guy cuz when you're not healthy,
you're also not practicing. And so he
didn't get those reps. To his credit, he
had never been injured in his in his
football career ever. And uh he had two
pretty significant injuries this year.
Battled back to be able to get on the
field for us. And that was uh that that
was good to see. That was good to see uh
you know his ambition and his drive to
I'm getting back out there. I'm not
going out like this. I want to play. And
so those were all positives, but to
analyze his season is is tough because
he uh really wasn't healthy beyond the
first game.
Yeah, you know, you you want guys that
play football well, but you want guys
that can play NFL football well. And uh
those traits are what drive a lot of
really great players. And and we do like
guys that are big enough, fast enough,
uh strong enough. You know, th you have
to have those things. You can't just
have desire. Desire with not any
physical traits. You know, you're going
to be doing my job and you're not going
to be uh playing NFL football for us.
But uh there's a marriage between the
two. Uh young guys like those two that
you mentioned, those guys have a lot of
future in front of them. And so we want
to build that future with them. And and
uh we believe that that'll be a really
positive future.
>> Yeah.
>> Okay.
>> Yeah. In in order to be a leader though,
you got to have skins on the wall and
you got to play effectively and the rest
of your teammates have to know that you
are producing at a high level. It's hard
to lead, you know, when you're not out
on the field or you're not producing
well. So, the first trait of a good
leader is production is actually
producing in a way that everyone
respects and wants to mimic. So, you
have to have that and then you have to
have, you know, the outward charisma and
you've also got to be willing to have
tough conversations with people and um
and so finding leaders sounds easy, but
there's a lot of components that go into
that and there's a lot of different
leadership styles that can work and and
I I think we've got some in inside of
our own building that'll continue to
evolve and grow in those roles. And then
if we can find some ready-made guys who
have the skins on the wall that come in
and help us in those areas, that'll be
good.
>> [snorts]
>> How much are you guys?
>> Um, unfortunately we're really far
along. You know, when your season goes
uh uh kaboot and you're uh you're out of
it, you're you're into this area a lot
quicker and uh we have stability on our
coaching staff and so we are far along.
We feel very confident in uh what we
want to do, who we'd like to do it with,
and we'll see if those things can come
together. But we feel like we're really
prepared for this event and for free
agency.
>> What are the most important?
>> The most important traits,
>> the number one trait, you have to love
football. You have to be playing
football because you enjoy the game. If
you're playing football just because of
what it brings you, it's it's normally
not going to be a long-term thing for
you. You have to be playing football
because you love doing it. And so, we
really want to know, does the guy love
football? If it didn't bring the things
that NFL football brings, which are
great, but if it didn't bring those
things, would he still be playing? would
he still be playing in the arena
football league or wanting to go to the
CFL or does he love the game? And then
we can build off of that. Does he have
the traits to play? Does he have the
speed, the size, the strength? Uh does
he have the production? Can he develop
the production? Those things all come
after does the guy enjoy being out
there, being in the locker room and
competing. And and that's the number one
thing we're trying to find. It's not
easy to put a pin on that. you you
nobody will raise their hand and say,
"Nah, I'm not about that." You know,
they they'll tell you they're about it,
but you have to judge their actions, how
they play, their interactions with their
teammates, the information you get from
the sources at the school, and you have
to divine whether the guy really enjoys
what he wants to do for a living.
Coach, how does it feel to be the
mostenior?
>> Well, it's strange. You know, I've got a
lot of respect for those three guys that
competed against the last couple years
and um obviously great coaches and have
had a lot of success and um so again,
it's a little strange, but I'm sure I'll
get used to it very quickly.
>> Is there any impactual impact to change
in the division or is it not really? Not
for me to sit here and say today. Maybe
those teams will evolve in different
ways than they have over the last couple
years. Kind of impossible for me to say,
but um exciting for us. We got
continuity, you know, and so we got to
capitalize on that and continue to build
and move forward.
>> Who's that?
How does a how does a to be first- time
play caller drill that
>> how do they curious how
>> I I think every team as I go through the
interview process with OC's I haven't
been in those obviously there's a lot of
Zooms going on these day and ages and so
probably less film involved and more
just speaking. Um
Dan's probably the best guy to talk to.
I I think you know he he went through
some of that this year, but um you know
I for like Dan Pitcher for example, you
know, he's he's been an integral part of
our process every single day he's been
here. Um you know, and he and I are are
lock step in terms of how the the plan
comes together, how we're calling it
during the game, all of our discussions
during the game. So I think a lot of
it's overstated when they talk about a
first-time play caller who hasn't called
plays before. I think that's that's
really overblown. Um, go find the best
person and leader that can put it all
together and the players respond to and
um, you know, those guys usually make
pretty good OC's.
>> How crucial is it?
>> Well, for me critical, but at the same
time, you know, it's I know there's a
difference in not calling plays and
calling plays and so so I I'm open to
that, you know, and and Cali went
through that, too. he got a head job and
and um so I get all that, but I'm happy
to have him back. You know, I was
hopeful he wasn't going to go anywhere.
Uh but again, I got a staff that's
worked for me for a long time. And so I
want them to have great opportunities. I
want them to always be searching for
more. And I think that's how you know
you got a great staff. They're not
content. They want to continue to do
more and they want more on their plate
and bigger opportunities. And so um you
know, I was I'm certainly open to that
with Dan.
Yeah, it's it's an ongoing conversation.
We we've all we we talk every day all
day, you know. Um so it's not like this
grand conversation that all of a sudden
comes up on January 5th or whatever day
it is. It's, you know, I I always know
how he feels and and uh we're really
close and so it's not a hard
conversation.
>> Yeah.
Sure.
So, making James Casey the run game
coordinator. Um, that's a title he's
earned. Um, one of the hardest workers
I've ever been around. I've said it a
million times, the best tight end coach
in the league, how he sees the game, I
think is is unique and it's important
for us to have on our staff. Every time
he opens his mouth, I value his opinion
because I know that it's coming from a
place of confidence and a lot of hard
work that he's put in to formulate that
opinion. Um, he's not just quick to
speak. He's not a guy who's throwing out
a thousand ideas because he wants to be
heard, he wants to talk. He's a guy
that's very thoughtful that when he
speaks. Um, our overall structure, we
still have a lot of people that we trust
in the run game that are so big part of
it. But I thought James was very
deserving of this title, uh, because of
the work he's put in over the last seven
years. And, um, James never asked me for
anything, you know, and and so I I just
I'm grateful to have him on our staff.
I'm grateful for him to have this title
and to be a lot part of our leadership
group moving forward and I'm just
excited for
>> James.
I do. I I do. I I think especially when
you look at our defensive staff light
years ahead of where we were last year,
we were talking scheme every day and
trying to get to speed on who our
current players are because a lot of
these guys were um obviously hadn't been
here. we just hired him and so now, you
know, we've immediately we we do we
didn't take a very long vacation. We
were back in the office very quickly for
the reason of being on top of free
agency and and this the draft process so
that we can get all the information, all
of our thoughts and feelings on players
to Duke and his staff and um so now we
can coexist together and and formulate
the best opinions for our team. And um
so I I feel I didn't exactly hear what
Duke said, but I know we are so much
further along in this process. we that
that's maybe the worst way to put it,
but just we're in a very confident place
right now as coaches. Um they always do
their work ahead of schedule, but uh
we're in a great place right now as
coaches and and uh can get that
information discussed.
>> You talk a lot about positions this time
of year and safety isn't usually amongst
them, but trend in the league with James
Hamilton. Do you feel like that is
becoming more of a premium position now
because of the way that some teams have
been able to make it really challenging
ones? Well, I think you you just, you
know, there those are really unique
players and so that those players that
you mentioned, Kyle Hamilton doesn't
walk through the door every single
draft, you know, and so um again, we're
still going through the process of
trying to find the best players that fit
us um at whatever position they play and
and those are three great players that
that pose a lot of challenges for
offenses that face them. We had we
didn't play Seattle, so I'm I'm not as
familiar. Um, but again, we're just
trying to find the best players that fit
us that can help us go in a
championship.
>> I know James was up next and I'll come
in.
>> What are your expectations from
expecting, hey,
this area?
>> Well, we go in, we we get with our
scouts and develop our thoughts on needs
we might have on both sides of the ball,
how they can help us, special teams as
well. Um, and then we jump into free
agency and we see we we get with, you
know, our our scouts do a great job
getting with these guys during that um,
negotiating process and figuring out
what fits for us and then you're ready
to shift if something doesn't work out
to another position. Um, it's a fun
process to be a part of. There's a lot
of work that goes into it. Uh, you got
to do a lot of work on a lot of players
because again, it's a very quick process
that happens very fast that can shift in
a moment's notice and you got to be
ready to go get another great player.
And so our guys, you know, our scouts
and coaches have done a great job with
the evaluation process and I feel like
we're in a good spot.
Yeah, I I think that they all happened
at different times. They weren't all day
one of free agency. Some of those guys,
uh, I remember getting Von Bell several
days in free agency. Um, there's been
others that have helped us that have
come later on. And so, you know, Dalton,
we got Dalton in in August this year,
you know, and he helped us. So, um,
we'll be prepared for the moment and and
see where it ends up for us.
>> Did you learn anything from that?
>> It was a lot of rookies at once. Uh,
there was a lot of on boarding. I'm I'm
curious if that experience has taught
you anything about how you might deal
with presumably another draft where
you're at.
>> I don't think so because I I think every
every year is just different. I I know I
say that regarding a lot of different
areas. Um but just putting young players
on the field, it could be a different
year as well. You know, there might not
be as many because I feel like we got a
lot of guys returning that we're have a
lot of confidence in and we'll see how
it fits with free agency in the draft
and I'm excited to see how that process
unfolds.
every time you add someone,
how do you go about the process making
sure you're identifying the right
>> every resource imaginable, you know,
it's whatever connection we have to
someone who's been around them, um,
whatever scouting report we had on them
coming out of out of college, um, there
can be a lot of different ways you
approach it. We try to utilize every
single one of them. You want to make
sure you're getting the right person
that walks in. You're not bringing in a
problem. you're you're bringing in one
of us, you know, someone that fits our
personalities in our locker room. And so
we spend a lot of time we're very
careful with who we bring in and try to
make those right decisions. Ben, I know
you had one.
>> Uh, this is in my genre of f favorite
questions about things that I learned
about Joe every year. Um, I wouldn't say
that I learned much about Joe this year.
I I love going to work side by side with
him every single day and um trying to
execute a plan that can help us win. And
he's one of the the biggest competitors
I've ever been around. And so as many
people that you can get like Joe um
around you, I think is critical. You
know, he's a champion. He knows how to
win. He's won before and he's he wants
to do whatever it takes to get back to
the top, you know, and let us go win a
Super Bowl. So, um I I can't say that I
learned anything from Joe this year, but
um every year we gain experiences side
by side with each other that um I
believe will help us win a championship.
>> Wow. Um it's a great question. What
derails quarterback development? Um I I
don't you know it's I think here we have
stability in our system with our
coaches. So their guys, our guys know
when they walk in the building what to
expect, whether it's a backup
quarterback or third string or scout
team guy. Um, we have a process that
that we feel works for us very well. Um,
I can't speak to what derails other
quarterbacks. I I that's that's not
really my my spot to do that. I've got a
lot of belief in our quarterback coach,
Brad Craig Thorp, and Dan Pitcher, has
been our quarterback coach. And um that
when guys walk in the building that
we're going to do everything we can to
develop and get the most out of them if
they step on the field.
Well, there's not necessarily because
there's a lot of head coaches that call
the plays and so I think that's that's
where it starts right there. There's a
lot of head coaches that call plays in
this league and um
there's a lot of criticism that comes
with calling plays. And so if you're
just the coordinator and you call the
plays um typically in three years you
better put your house in the market.
You're either going to be a head coach
or you're going to be fired. I mean
that's that's the way it goes. I'm not
saying that at a jest like that's that's
the truth. That's how it is. And so um
it's just unique position that um draws
a lot of criticism and that's kind of
the fun part of it. I I love doing
something that people are passionate
about and um and it's it's you know it's
I don't know if I answered your question
clearly but I think it's you could write
a whole story on that that topic.
You know, it's it's a topic that I I
haven't had to deal with because we've
had continuity. You know, I had Brian my
first five years and Pitch was our
quarterback coach and we've had him the
last two going on three. So, I'm not the
best to speak on that. Um I'm I'm happy
with where we're at. I'm happy with the
process we have and the people we have
involved in it.
It
>> it's a great question. Um I think
everyone would probably give you a
slightly different answer because of of
how their place is. And um try to be
there for these guys. Do do I always do
enough? I I don't know if I always do
enough. I honestly don't. And you hear
players that have gone through a
significant injury that when you were
there for them or someone was there for
them, they're always very loud. you
know, this person, I appreciated that.
That really helped me through the
process and that always resonates with
me. I'm not going to sit here and say
that I I feel like I've been perfect in
that area. Um, it's a great topic you
brought up because it is it is
important. It's not a throwaway. Um, we
do have to support these guys when they
go through that stuff. It's um, you hope
it never it leads to a tragedy, but um,
you know, I know that that's a tough
tough topic that that we got to continue
to be better at.
fantastic. What did you learn from him?
>> Um, a lot everything, you know, and
obviously I had great mentors before
Shawn, but working for Shawn, he just
showed you you there there's a
transparency level there with the head
coach that can exist. Um, he was I don't
remember how 31 maybe when I started
working with him, I think. And he very
transparent. He he told us what he was
going through, what he was feeling, what
he was dealing with players, and that
was unique to me. I I hadn't been in the
league very long. And so to see a young
guy that it's okay to to share with
everybody what what he's dealing with,
be pretty transparent with the players,
uh form good relationship with the
players on and off the field, that's
okay to do as well. And there was just a
belief that Shawn had and whatever came
out of his mouth, everybody around him
believed it. He empowered everybody
around him. I remember as an assistant
coach, whether I was assistant receivers
or quarterbacks, you always felt like
valued and empowered. Um, he let you
know that. And so, again, I'm I'm
grateful for having worked for him for
two years. I learned a lot from him. I
don't think it's any secret why people,
you know, there's the joke that if you
had a cup of coffee, you're going to go
be head coach. There's truth to that
because when you spend time with Shawn,
it rubs off on you. You believe
everything in the process that he does
and then you take that process and you
convey in an interview because you
believe in it. You're not just guessing
what it looks like to go be a a Super
Bowl contender, Super Bowl. You're not
guessing. You know, you you've seen the
groundwork laid. And um that's what we
took here to Cincinnati in our third
year. We were playing for a Super Bowl
because we believed it and it it we knew
what it looked like and we knew how to
get there and and we know how to get
back there. And so I can go on Sean for
days and weeks, but um he's meant a lot
to me and I think he's a great coach.
He's impacted a lot of other coaches.
I I I don't want to speak too soon on
where he's at for 26. Um I know he's
progressing nicely as the as the season
went on and as we got into the off
season. Um but I don't have an update
for you today on how that's going.
>> Go ahead. You
>> second year.
How much I I asked this question
earlier. How much is now having more
defensive staff when you've seen on film
ping?
What does that do as far as identifying
players who are culture and not just
>> I think just for having coached those
guys for a year, our defensive staff,
they know exactly what we have in the
building. A lot of young players coming
on, a lot of veterans, how they fit with
us. And so now what are our needs? And
I'm not going to get into what our needs
are, but um guys that can walk in here
and help us. And these interviews that
we do with these guys help us. They get
we get to know these people. Um we get
to put a name with the face as we watch
the tape and and all the traits we're
looking for. And so, um, it's exciting
to have that staff back for year two
and, um, to be able to tack the draft
with these guys. I think that's that's
that's a lot of fun for me and for them.
Someone over here has
>> your quarterback evaluation up a couple
notches with
>> I Yeah, I think that's fair to say. You
know, it's um,
obviously Joe's Joe Flack will be a free
agent. Um, and so we got to evaluate
everybody that's that's out there and I
don't know where to fall. I don't know
it'll fall in free agency or the draft,
but um certainly something we we're
going to be paying attention to.
>> Press
>> I mean press is he's he's been in that
role before. Um I think he's an
incredible coach. I've never worked for
him worked with him, but but the people
that have been around him are always
quick to tell me that. I know Ben thinks
highly of him. Um, I think it's a great
relationship with he and Ben. I I think
the world Ben I worked with Ben for four
years in Miami. Um, been around press my
whole life. So, I think those are two
people that do it the right way. Um,
that'll work really well together. They
got a great staff there in Chicago.
Ben's done a great job with that group.
And so, you know, we don't we don't play
him in the regular season so I can pull
for him, you know, in the regular
season, but um, I'm excited for the
opportunity Press has got. Press is
ready for that. And again, he's he's uh
like everybody had bumps in his career
and now he's now he's at a place where
um I'm happy he's there. I think Chicago
is a great organization, great head
coach, and happy to see him flourish
there.
>> You guys
want
>> Well, how they view the game, their
football IQ. just when you hear them
talk football, um, you kind of get their
passion for the game sometimes from
people around them, you know, you try
your best. Anybody I got a relationship
with trying to ask about a player, same
with their scouts, try to learn more
about that guy. Ultimately, yeah, you
want someone that loves football, you
want someone that elevates everyone
around him. So, you want someone who's a
force multiplier. You you put a guy at
this spot, man, the two guys next to him
are going to be better players because
of his football IQ, his communication
skills, his talent level, um, raises
everyone up a notch. And so when you can
get a whole group of guys that are like
that, um, it elevates an entire unit and
it elevates entire team. And so those
are the types of guys that we're looking
for.
>> In that regard, linebacker, how
important will be adding a veteran
presence, not just for adding to the
room, what it could do for Barrett and
Demetrius as they need to come.
>> I think we're open to however it will
fall, you know, and so again, without
getting too early into it, we're still
in February. We're not in free agency
yet draft, but I'm excited about the
development of those two guys. I think
they got um some experience that that
you couldn't have bought with them on
the sidelines and so they learned from
that. They have really bright futures
and now we'll just see how it falls for
the rest of the spring and and see what
the competition looks like in OTA
offense that you
>> Well, I think there's things we need to
be better at. We we didn't take care of
the football this year and so it doesn't
matter what kind of talent we have on
offense. We we did a poor job um in the
turnover margins on both sides. Defense
got better as the year went on, but
offensively, you know, we didn't finish
in an area that puts you in the playoffs
or wins divisions or anything like that.
So, I think forget about the talent
level. Those are things that as coaches
and players, we got to do a great job
capitalizing on to give ourselves the
best chance. And um you know, we we did
hit the top of how we wanted to play in
any area on our football team. And
that's that's all three phases. And so,
um, I do think that we're we're we've
got a lot of talent. There's probably
not a lot to do on offense with our
personnel. Um, doesn't mean we won't
evaluate guys that can help us. Uh, but
again, I I do want us to continue to
play better on that side of the ball to
help everybody.
>> Oh, uh, you know, I I can draw
inspiration from a lot of different
things. Um, you know, I probably speak a
lot about my dad. My dad inspired me
just the way he lives his life and um
he's gotten the most out of his children
I think and uh what he's wanted from his
life. He was my first coach and
everything I did. I saw the way he was
an example for his kids. I'm at that
moment now. A kid going into high school
next year where you're trying to make
sure did I do everything I could to get
him ready for real life. And so you
think back on lessons uh for my dad. I
can think about the other day my son has
it's freezing. We all live in
Cincinnati. It's freezing right now.
It's it's uh brutal. Okay. and uh
probably 20 degrees and he text me, can
we go throw at six o'clock at night? And
I almost made the excuse, it's too dark.
It's going to be dark in 20 minutes. We
can't do it. But I thought my that's not
what my dad would do. He'd go throw with
me. So I picked the football. We went
out to Kilgore Elementary School and
threw and had a good time. So great
question.
>> Yeah.
>> Sure.
Well, I think that's it's important in
this profession to have people around
you that support you and love you and
have brought you up the right way. And I
know Preston and I are fortunate to have
that family and so that means a lot to
us.
All good. All right.